<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Homes on женатик</title>
    <link>http://genat.uk/home/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Homes on женатик</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2017 Vladimir Kiselev</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 20 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://genat.uk/home/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://genat.uk/home/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://genat.uk/home/about/</guid>
      <description>About 
I am leading the Cellular Genetics Informatics team at the Wellcome Sanger Institute. Our team provides efficient access to cutting-edge analysis methods, environments and pipelines for Cellular Genetics programme, which leads a number of world-class research initiatives including the Human Cell Atlas, Human Induced Pluripotent Stem Cell Initiative and Human BioMolecular Atlas Program. We work with large amounts of single-cell RNA sequencing and microscopy imaging data.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Recent Posts</title>
      <link>http://genat.uk/home/posts/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://genat.uk/home/posts/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Projects</title>
      <link>http://genat.uk/home/projects/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://genat.uk/home/projects/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Links</title>
      <link>http://genat.uk/home/links/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://genat.uk/home/links/</guid>
      <description>Data Visualization  D3.js p5js UK Data Explorer Лаборатория Данных Interactive Data Visualization for the Web XVIVO - Scientific Animation   Just cool  Collectionerus Hubble Space Telescope flibusta Dan Foreman-Mackey Bayes&amp;rsquo; Theorem showmystreet VisitBritain   Bioinformatics  Karl Broman RExRepos NextGenetics NGS tutorials Getting Genetics Done   Academia  Designing conference posters   Machine Learning  Лекция Дмитрия Ветрова о математике больших данных   Tech  Video -&amp;gt; GIF converter GIF maker Google Fusion Tables CodePen Free Online IDE and Terminal   Health  Do you want to get rid of your knee pain?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Contact</title>
      <link>http://genat.uk/home/contact/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://genat.uk/home/contact/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>