<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Life on женатик</title>
    <link>http://genat.uk/categories/life/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Life on женатик</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2017 Vladimir Kiselev</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 22 Jan 2017 02:12:52 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://genat.uk/categories/life/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>New website theme</title>
      <link>http://genat.uk/post/2017-01-22-new-website-theme/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 22 Jan 2017 02:12:52 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://genat.uk/post/2017-01-22-new-website-theme/</guid>
      <description>I have just updated this website with an academic theme and it looks amazing! I&amp;rsquo;m glad I&amp;rsquo;ve tried it. Now I not only have a solid functionality behind the website but also quite a pretty website&amp;rsquo;s face. I am convinced that Hugo is great and very fast for building websites. Please do not hesitate to try it out!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hello, World!</title>
      <link>http://genat.uk/post/2017-01-16-hello-world/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Jan 2017 08:54:39 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://genat.uk/post/2017-01-16-hello-world/</guid>
      <description>I haven’t written anything to this blog during 2016. So one of my New Year’s resolutions will be to start recording my work updates and personal thoughts here. I have also updated this blog to blogdown, so now I will be able to easily share my R wisdom with you. Here is what I will be able to plot and deploy in the blink of an eye!
## ======================================== ## circlize version 0.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How medicine turns into advertising</title>
      <link>http://genat.uk/post/2015-10-20-how-medicine-turns-into-advertising/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Oct 2015 20:23:30 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://genat.uk/post/2015-10-20-how-medicine-turns-into-advertising/</guid>
      <description>I have just learnt about some tension growing around Theranos biotech startup. Looks like their advertisement strategy worked very well, giving them more than 400 million dollars of investments. However, now the whole technology is under a big question. The topic is familiar to me because last year I took part in the Biotechnology YES competition and my team presented a similar idea of diagnosing cancer relapse from a blood test.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>